Guide to the P. Adem Carroll Papers 1964-2018 (bulk, 2000-2010) MS 3212
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Audiovisual, 2002-2015
  - Series IV.A. Digital Formats, 2002-2015
    - [5-10] Religion and Violence: Untangling the Roots of Conflict Conference, 2008 January (Digital folder MS 3212)
      4. James Carroll, "The Non-Violent God: Reforming Theology as a Way to Peace" (WAV audio file; 1 hour)
      5. Susannah Heschel, "Religion and Violence: Finding Prophetic Voice" (WAV audio file; 1 hour, 13 minutes)
      6. Closing Panel Discussion (WAV audio file; 1 hour)
    - ACLU Dissent Freedom Files with Lewis Black (RESTRICTED), 2006 (Offsite-box 6)
      Directed and produced by Jeremy Kagan.
    - Aliens Among Us (RESTRICTED), 2009 (Offsite-box 6)
      Film produced by Martina Radwan.
    - American Muslims: Fact vs. Fiction (RESTRICTED), 2015 (Offsite-box 6)
      Produced by PBS Learning Media and Unity Productions Foundation.
    - Nadia's Ramadan (RESTRICTED), 2015 (Offsite-box 6)
      Produced by PBS Learning Media and Unity Productions Foundation, a "short film about Muslim holidays for the public school classroom."
    - Persons of Interest (RESTRICTED), 2003 (Offsite-box 6)
      Directed by Alison MacLean and Tobias Perse; produced by Lawrence Konner.
    - Solitary Confinement: Torture in Your Backyard (RESTRICTED), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
      Produced by the National Religious Campaign Against Torture (NRCAT)
  - Series IV.B. Cassette Tapes, 2002-2003
    The subseries consists of a set of audiocassette tapes, which are an oral recitation of the Quran, as well as a set of videocassette VHS tapes that include various recordings or documentaries on 9/11 and post-9/11 detentions.
    The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Audiocassette tapes (RESTRICTED), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
      Set of 19 cassette tapes held in green carrier, which labels in Arabic. Appears to be a recitation of the Quran by imam Ibrahim Al-Akhdar.
    - VHS cassette tapes (RESTRICTED), 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 6)
      A set of 15 VHS tapes which largely include reports from various news stations on detainees or documentaries about detainees after 9/11. Many tapes include the inscription "Martha" or "Martha's copy." Annotations are noted on the cassette's side. The items are:
      1. MDC (Metropolitan Detention Center), 04/06/02
      2. ZDF(Zweites Deutsches Fernsehen) about Shokrera, 09/11/02
      3. Nightline, ABC News, Detainees, 12/27/02
      4. Fet Det Demo, 1st Copy, 02/16/02
      5. MDC, 05/04/02
      6. Fed Det Demo, 03/09/02
      7. MCD Demo, 04/27/02
      8. Stars, Stripes and Human Rights, 05/10/03
      9. Fed Det Demo, 02/09/02
      10. MDC Demo, 03/16/02
      11. MDC Demo - full copy of Hi8 (no time code), 03/30/02
      12. Nightline ABC News, Detainees, 12/27/02
      13. Fed Det Demo, 1st Copy - Full, 02/23/02
      14. Interfaith iftar, with Javid Esak, Naeem Baig, Jay Rock, and Anna Vigen (note included), December 2001.
      15. Points of Attack, dir. Kathleen Foster, 2004
- Series V. Artifacts, 2007, 2015, undated
  The series cosnsist of physical artifacts, including a Bosnian army patch, a certificate, and a tile with Arabic script.
  The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Bosnian army patch, Undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 17)
  - Certificate, 2015 July (Offsite-box 5, Folder 20)
    Certificate awarded to Reverend Dr. Alfonso Wyatt at the July 7, 2015 Queens Unity Iftar. Carroll sat on the event's coordinating committee.
  - Desktop clock in form of a book, undated (Offsite-box 5)
  - Keychain with image of Pakistan flag, undated (Offsite-box 5)
  - Tile with Arabic script, Undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 18)
  - Tote bag from 32nd ICNA -MAS Convention, 2007 (Offsite-box 5)